Macarena Waidele /

Associate

Practice Area: Corporate Law

macarena.waidele@ocl.cl

Macarena has specialized in private law, mainly civil and commercial matters. Her work covers all aspects of corporate law, such as insurance, reinsurance, public and private tenders, international transactions, foreign trade and customs. She has been part of the team in mergers, acquisitions, business restructurings, shareholders agreements and counsel to investors in private investment funds. Her work is mainly in the area of aquiculture and maritime law, specifically contracts and the registration of aquiculture concessions. She has been a participant in matters of foreign trade and customs regulations and administrative appeals before the National Customs Service.

WORK HISTORY

2018 - present / Ovalle Consejeros Legales

2015 - 2017 / Carey y Cía. Ltda.

2013 - 2015 / Carey y Cía. Ltda. - Intern

EDUCATION

Contract Law Refresher Course, University of Chile, 2017 B.A. in Legal and Social Sciences. Adolfo Ibáñez University. Admissions: 2016

ACTIVIDADES ACADÉMICAS

Aid in the Process and Procedure Course (Procedural Law II), Adolfo Ibáñez University.

Aid in the Politics and Thought Course (Philosophy), Adolfo Ibáñez University. Aid in the Critical Reading Course, Adolfo Ibáñez University.

PUBLICATIONS

- Co-author of articles on the preventive control of mergers by the National Department of Economic Justice and new regulations on payment cards issued by the Central Bank, published in Legal Development in Latin America (LALD) by the American Bar Association (ABA), 2017.
- Co-author of articles on insurance regulations, foreign investment law and the bill of law on the structural reform to the Chilean insurance regulatory agency, published by the ABA in LALD in 2016.
- Co-author of an article of open corporation corporate governance standards, published by the ABA in LALD, ABA, 2015.

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English